Guide to the Rose Pastor Stokes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Rose Pastor Stokes papers
1900-1993
MS 573
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, printed material, clippings, and other papers of Rose Pastor Stokes, writer, artist, and radical political and social activist. Much of the material relates to Stokes's activities and involvement with various radical groups, including the American Communist Party and the Socialist Party. The correspondence reflects these involvements and contains many letters exchanged with American political radicals, labor leaders, and anarchists from the early 20th century. Also included are research materials of John M. Whitcomb relating to Rose Pastor Stokes.
Stokes, Rose Pastor, 1879-1933
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John M. Whitcomb; and Richard Pastor, 1993.
Existence and Location of Copies
Entire collection [excluding Series I, Box 9, Folders 12, 13, and 18; Series V, Drawings (Box 12 and Folio); and additions since 1984] is also available on microfilm (6944 frames on 8 reels, 35mm.) from Scholarly Resources, Inc., Wilmington, Delaware.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series and additions: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Printed Material. IV. Subject File. V. Drawings.
Scope and Contents
Rose Pastor Stokes' papers consist of correspondence, 1905-1933; writings, including manuscripts and published material, 1900-1958; printed material, consisting mostly of newspaper clippings, 1904-1953; drawings, some of which were either exhibited or published, 1923-1932; and miscellaneous material involving Rose Pastor Stokes' literary interests and political activities, 1904-1944.
Most of the correspondence relates either to Rose Pastor Stokes' political activities or to her literary endeavors, both of which are in general politically oriented. Correspondents of note include: Leonard Abbott, Alexander Bittleman, Eugene V. Debs, Max Eastman, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Henry Ford, Kahlil Gibran, Emmaus Goldman, Upton Sinclair, Margaret Sanger, and Oswald Garrison Villard. Correspondence with James Graham Phelps Stokes and Jerome Isaac Romaine, Rose Pastor Stokes' husbands, and Olive Tilford Dargan, author and close personal friend of Mrs. Stokes, is of particular importance in relation to Rose Pastor Stokes' personal life. Among the writings is a copy of her unfinished autobiography which spans the period from 1879 to 1905. In addition, there is interesting material about her activities before 1920 which includes information on her views on socialism, on her participation in several workers' strikes and in the campaign to distribute birth control information to the public, and on her activities in support of various radical leaders such as Patrick Quinlan, Emma Goldman, and Margaret Sanger.
See also: ANSON PHELPS STOKES FAMILY PAPERS, box 225, folder 83 for letters from Rose Pastor Stokes to Helen Phelps Stokes.
Biographical / Historical
Rose Pastor Stokes (1879-1933), born in Augustowe, Poland, immigrated to the United States in 1890. For the next twelve years she worked in a Cleveland cigar factory during the day and followed a program of self-education at night. In 1903 she moved to New York City and became a feature writer for the Jewish Daily News. Soon after her arrival in New York, she interviewed the young millionaire socialist, James Graham Phelps Stokes. Out of this interview grew the romance which culminated in their marriage July 18, 1905. In the years that followed, Rose Pastor Stokes became known as a radical and a political activist. Aligned with the socialist movement at the beginning of her career, she moved steadily to the left, ultimately becoming a member of the American Communist Party. Her increasingly radical activities led to an estrangement with her husband, however, and in 1925 Stokes obtained a divorce from his wife. Rose was married again in 1927 to Jerome Isaac Romaine, a communist activist. She died in Germany in 1933 while undergoing treatment for cancer.
The following biographical sketch was written by John M. Whitcomb, who donated these papers to Yale. Additional information on Rose Pastor Stokes may be found in the Dictionary of American Biography.
ROSE HARRIET PASTOR
Born July 18, 1879 in Augustowe, Poland.
Removed to London, England in 1882.
Removed to Cleveland, Ohio, 1890.
Removed to New York City in 1903; worked for JEWISH DAILY NEWS.
Married to James Graham Phelps Stokes July 18, 1905.
Divorced from Mr. Stokes in 1925.
Remarried to Jerome Isaac Romaine in 1927.
Died in Germany June 20, 1933.
1. Childhood, years until marriage: Covered by uncompleted autobiography.
2. Years 1903-1905 in New York City working for JEWISH DAILY NEWS; friendship formed with Israel Zevin of the newspaper staff.
3. Early married life at "Caritas Island", Stamford and 88 Grove Street, New York City:
Worked as a lecturer for the INTERCOLLEGIATE SOCIALIST SOCIETY which was organized by Jack London, Upton Sinclair and Graham Stokes; lecture tours went to many campuses of the United States and many friendships were formed during these travels (which were also conducted by Graham Stokes). As a result, many active socialists, some active anarchists and syndicalists (I.W.W.) were guests at "Caritas Island". Other visitors included liberals, literary figures of the time. A noteworthy guest was Maxim Gorky in 1906; he apparently came with Leroy and Miriam Finn Scott and Mrs. Scott acted as an interpreter because she, herself, was Russian.
Graham Stokes "built with his own hands" two small houses on the island; these were for his friends from his days at the University Settlement House in New York City - Leroy Scott and English (William English) Walling. The Scott house is still standing. Walling was the joint founder of the N.A.A.C.P., following a trip to Springfield, Illinois, where he witnessed a Negro lynching.
During these years Mrs. Stokes was active in organizing the hotel workers and dressmakers in N.Y.C. She was in demand as an agitational speaker. She was also very much involved in birth-control activities with Margaret Sanger and Emma Goldman. As a prominent woman of the time, she was asked to join the HETERODOXY SOCIETY; this organization included many prominent women from cultural activities, and was not limited to people active in the socialist movement. Mrs. Stokes wrote several plays during these years; one of these, "The Woman Who Wouldn't", was presented by the Washington Square Players. She also contributed to such publications as The Masses (Editor, Max Eastman).
During the year 1913, Mrs. Stokes worked in behalf of Patrick Quinlan who had been sentenced to prison during the Paterson (N.J.) strike. Persons of note associated with this period of Mrs. Stokes' life, letters from and to whom included in the collection were:
William English Walling (Socialist, lecturer, writer, N.A.A.C.P.)
Miriam Finn Scott (L.S., novelist, Socialist)
Eugene V. Debs
Upton Sinclair (writer, I.S.S., Socialist)
Olive Tilford Dargan (poetess, novelist in 1930's under name of Fielding Burke: "Call Home the Heart": devoted friend of RPS; now 100 years old)
Horace Traubel (poet, biographer and friend of Walt Whitman, publisher of the "Conservator")
Leonard Abbott (professional Anarchist, associate of Emma Goldman, publisher, associated with the Ferrer Center)
Elizabeth Gurley Flynn (I.W.W. organizer, common-law wife of the anarchist leader, Carlo Tresca; died in Moscow as Chairman of the Communist Party of U.S. in 1960's; spent a summer with her infant son on "Caritas Island" as guest of Graham and RPS; active in defense of Sacco and Vanzetti)
Lilian Wald (Director of Henry Street Settlement House, N.Y.C.)
Rose Strunsky (Lorwin) (L.L., Socialist, writer on economics, syndicalism, etc.)
Kate Barnard (Commissioner of Charities for Oklahoma)
Harry W. Laidler (Secretary of Intercollegiate Socialist Society which later changed its name to League for Industrial Democracy) (see folder "Political Organizations: Intercollegiate Socialist Society, Harry W. Laidler")
Paula Jakobi (H. Society) (see folder: "Medical Matters")
Ida Rauh (wife of Max Eastman)
Max Eastman (writer, supporter and translator of works of Leon Trotsky, attended Debs' trial with RPS, editor of The Masses .)
Seymour Stedman (lawyer, National Executive Committee of Socialist Party, defender of people prosecuted for sedition during WWI)
George Strobell (Socialist, brother-in-law of Henry Demarest Lloyd, helped organize I.S.S.0) (see "Patrick Quinlan Legal Case")
Arturo Giovannitti (Anarchist, poet, involved in Lawrence strike, 1912)
Ben Reitman (Anarchist, common-law husband of Emma Goldman) (see "Mother Earth Publishing Co." folder)
Albert Rhys Williams (Socialist, minister, war correspondent for "Outlook", 1917, "Through the Russian Revolution")
Oswald Garrison Villard (Editor of the "Nation")
4. Years 1917-1918, opposes entry of U.S. into World War I, sentenced to 10 year prison term for seditious utterances; Debs trial and sentence to prison.
Mabel D. Curry (wife of Socialist professor in Terre Haute, Ind.; devoted friend of E. V. Debs whom she visited at Atlanta Penitentiary; RPS notes "Debs was in love with her")
5. Years 1919-1933:
Assisted in the organization of the Communist Party of U.S.; attended Bridgeman, Michigan secret convention in 1922, for which she was subject to prosecution under Michigan laws; delegate to the 4th Congress of the Comintern in Leningrad and Moscow, Nov.-Dec. 1922, at which she acted as "Reporter for the Negro Commission", presided over by G. Safarov - the documents covering this episode are in the collection, where Mrs. Stokes used the cover name of "Sacha".
During this period Mrs. Stokes appears to have been an organizer and worker for the Communist Party. Her health began to fail and she withdrew from active party work about the time of her divorce in 1925. She became interested in drawing and exhibited at the SOCIETY OF INDEPENDENT ARTISTS in N.Y.C. in 1925; a portrait called "Anna" was done by her and illustrated in the catalogue of the exhibit; apparently she was encouraged by the artist Gibran, who wrote The Prophet.
After her divorce from Graham Stokes, Mrs. Stokes lived, for a time, with Jeanette Pearl, who I believe to have once been the common-law wife of Louis Fraina, early leader of the Communist Party of the U.S. (Fraina changed his name to Lewis Corey and was, for many years, a professor at Antioch College, during which time he wrote a number of books on political and economic affairs.) In 1927, Mrs. Stokes married Jerome I. Romaine, a language teacher who later edited the Communist magazine, Political Affairs (he had once been the husband of Frances Winwar, Pulitzer Prize winner with her biographical novel Poor Splendid Wings ). Romaine changed his name to Victor J. Jerome. Mrs. Stokes called herself Mrs. J. I. Romaine when she resided in New York City, but when living in her cottage in Westport, Connecticut, she retained the name Rose Pastor Stokes. In 1933 she died of cancer while being treated in a clinic in Germany. A memorial service, with political overtones, was held in New York City (see documents), under-written by many people of prominence.
Jeanette Pearl
Maximilian Cohen (Communist dentist, party organizer)
Scott Nearing (onetime Communist candidate for Governor of New Jersey, prolific writer with a left-wing slant)
Alexander Bittleman (Communist Party professional, writer)
Max Bedacht (Communist Party professional)
Charles Ruthenberg (Secretary of the Communist Party of US.; died in 1927; ashes buried in Kremlin wall) (see "Political Organizations - Workers Party of America" folder)
Louis Boudin (Communist theorist, lawyer, writer)
Jack Carney (Irish revolutionist, associated with Irish Communist writer in Chicago - James Larkin)
Tom Mooney (sentenced for supposed involvement in 1916 San Francisco parade explosion, prisoner at San Quenton) (see Subject File: "Rose Pastor Stokes Testimonial and Concert")
APPENDIX I. PHOTOGRAPHS from the albums of JAMES GRAHAM PHELPS STOKES and ROSE PASTOR STOKES
1 --- Gleichman's Cigar Factory, Cleveland, Ohio - Spring 1896, Workers
2 --- Dance at Toledo, Ohio - Sunday evening, Oct. 27, 1901 - Rose H. Pastor
3 --- Girlhood friend of Rose Pastor, Cleveland, Ohio
4 --- Girlhood friend of Rose Pastor, Cleveland
5-6 --- Girlhood friend
7 --- Robert Emanuel Pastor (half-brother, RHP) and dog, Cleveland
8 --- Schoolboys, Cleveland - Robert E. Pastor, rear row, extreme right
9 --- Anna Levin (Weislander) Pastor, mother of Rose Harriet Pastor
10 --- James Graham Phelps Stokes as a child, New York City
11 --- J. G. P. Stokes as a young boy
12 --- J. G. P. Stokes as a young man
13 --- Rose Pastor Stokes in wedding dress, July 1905 - Brick House, Noroton, Conn.
14 --- Rose Pastor Stokes, J. G. P. Stokes - Wedding picture, Brick House, Noroton Point, Conn., July 1905, home of Anson Phelps Stokes Sr.
15 --- Rose P. Stokes, J. G. P. Stokes outside Brick House, Noroton
16 --- Robert E. Pastor, Lillian Pastor, Cecil Pastor, Bernard Pastor at Brick House, Noroton, Stokes Wedding - half brothers and half sister of RPS
17 --- Rose P. Stokes on S.S. "Cedric" - Wedding trip to Europe, July 1905
18 --- Rose P. Stokes on S.S. "Cedric" (White Star Line)
19 --- Frederick Brockhausen, JGPS, Victor Berger, RPS left foreground; Socialists at Convention, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, July 1907
20 --- JGPS, Brockhausen, Milwaukee, Wisconsin
21 --- Brockhausen, Milwaukee Socialist - JGPS
22 --- Rose P. Stokes, Milwaukee
23 --- Walter Weyl, author, with son Nathaniel (friend of JGPS at University Settlement)
24 --- Group of visitors, "Summerbrook", Adirondacks, N.Y. - home of John Martins; J. G. P. Stokes, center; Upton Sinclair, extreme right - summer 1907
25 --- Group at "Summerbrook", Adirondacks - Ernest Howard Crosby, bareheaded in center (Philosophical Anarchist, author, lecturer)
26 --- John Martin and Borzoi, "Summerbrook"
27 --- Prestonia Mann Martin, John Martin, Rose P. Stokes "Summerbrook"
28 --- Visitors at "Summerbrook" - rear row, standing, JGP Stokes at center, Darwin J. Meserole (Brooklyn Socialist) at extreme right; Rose P. Stokes seated on floor with black tie; Prestonia Mann Martin seated in chair at center
29 --- Visitors dining at "Summerbrook"- John Spargo, extreme left; Edwin Slosson, foreground; Harriet Stanton Match (Feminist) in black, third from right
30 --- Rose P. Stokes with Borzoi, "Summerbrook"
31 --- Rose P. Stokes rowing on lake, "Summerbrook"
32 --- John Spargo (Socialist) and JGP Stokes, "Summerbrook"
33 --- Visitor, "Summerbrook"
34 --- Prestonia Mann Martin, John Martin, Upton Sinclair "Summerbrook"
35 --- Rose Pastor Stokes at desk, apartment, Grand Street and Norfolk Ave., New York
36 --- Robert Hunter and children, Noroton Heights, Connecticut
37 --- Vladimir Reznikof, blind poet - protege of Rose P. Stokes
38 --- Group at Minersville, Pennsylvania (Strike at Coombe Garment Co., women and girls, May 16, 1911) Eugene Debs, rear right; Con Foley, Elizabeth G. Flynn
39 --- Mrs. Rockwell (Kathleen) Kent
40 --- Stamford, Connecticut - 275th Anniversary Celebration, June 10, 1916, Main Street at Suburban Avenue - Andrew Carnegie, third from right; JGPS rear
41 --- J. G. P. Stokes, wedding party, Brick House, Noroton Point
42 --- Stokes family reunion, Anson P. Stokes Camp, St. Regis, Adirondacks, N. Y.
43 --- Stokes family reunion
44 --- Anna Strunsky Walling with first child
45 --- William Fletcher as young man (later husband of Lillian Pastor)
46 --- William Fletcher and Lillian Pastor Fletcher
47 --- Gertrude Traubel, daughter of Horace Traubel (biographer of Walt Whitman)
48 --- Horace Traubel, biographer, printer, poet
49 --- Henri LaFontaine (Belgian Socialist), Mrs. LaFontaine, Charlotte Perkins Gilman (Feminist, Socialist), Houghton Gilman - North Carolina Socialist Conv.
50 --- Wooden bridge to "Caritas Island", Stamford, Conn., Spring, 1913
51 --- J. G. P. Stokes house, "Caritas Island" (built 1906) - south elevation
52 --- Stokes House, "Caritas Island" - south elevation
53 --- Stokes House, "Caritas Island" - north elevation
54 --- View of Wallack's Point from "Caritas Island" - Lederle House, white house in center (Lederle was Health Commissioner of New York City)
55 --- Wooden bridge to "Caritas Island" - Leroy Scott House at right
56 --- Bernard Pastor (youngest Pastor child) on snowshoes, "Caritas Island"
57 --- Panoramic view - Leroy Scott House, left; William English Walling House, right
58 --- Leroy Scott House and breakwater - "Caritas Island"
59 --- Stokes House - south elevation
60 --- View of lagoon and wooden bridge to Wallack's Point
61 --- View of Schofield Island from "Caritas Island"
62 --- Driveway turnaround, Stokes House
63 --- View of outer breakwater, stone pier (center) - bathing beach at right
64 --- Rose P. Stokes on "Mother Rock"
65 --- Rocks on shore of "Caritas Island"
66 --- View from 2nd floor of Stokes House (west side)
67 --- View from 2nd floor of Stokes House (south side)
68 --- View from 2nd floor, Master's Bedroom (west side) towards Schofield Island
69 --- View from 2nd floor (west side) towards Shippan Point
70 --- JGP Stokes at signal pole - outer breakwater in distance
71 --- Rose Pastor Stokes (center) in wedding dress - taken later on "Caritas Island"
72 --- RPS with bouquet ("the roses that I was presented with at my second big meeting at the beginning of the Hotel Workers' Strike, New York City")
73 --- [missing]
74 --- George Goebel (Socialist) shooting bow and arrow, 1906
75 --- [missing]
76 --- Bernard Pastor with bow and arrow, 1906, "Caritas Island"
77 --- Rose P. Stokes raking; Bernard Pastor with wheelbarrow, "Caritas Island"
78 --- Howard Brubaker and Robert Bruere playing croquet, 1906, "Caritas Island"
79 --- Howard Brubaker and Robert Bruere (from "A Club", New York City)
80 --- Fishing off the bridge for flounders; Rose P. Stokes at right
81 --- Kellogg Durland, author (friend of JGPS at University Settlement)
82 --- Front: JGP Stokes, Edwin Slosson, William Noyes (Prof. Teachers College, N.Y.) Sept. 19 Rear: Robert Rives LaMonte, John Corbin, Rufus W. Weeks
83 --- Arthur Bullard, author - "Caritas Island"
84 --- Arthur Bullard, Rose P. Stokes
85 --- Lillian Pastor Fletcher on the lawn, "Caritas Island"
86 --- Francis Hackett, Irish author, editor
87 --- Arthur Bullard, author ("Albert Edwards": novel, "Comrade Yetta")
88 --- Israel Zevin, editor "Jewish Daily News" - employer of Rose H. Pastor
89 --- Bernard Pastor in bathing suit, "Caritas Island"
90 --- Sonia Levien - later lawyer, scenario writer in Hollywood (Mrs. Carl Hovey)
91 --- Anna Strunsky Walling, Rose Strunsky Lorwin, sisters - "Caritas Island"
92 --- Rose P. Stokes at south side of Stokes House, 1913 (Photo by Col. Weber)
93 --- Rose P. Stokes with bow and arrow
94 --- William J. Ghent (author, editor), Mrs. Ghent, Mrs. Leroy Scott, Leroy Scott, Rose P. Stokes, JGP Stokes - "Caritas Island"
95 --- German Captain of Hamburg-Amerika S.S. "Moltke", 1908 - Stokes trip to Europe
96 --- Kate Barnard, Oklahoma Commissioner of Charities
97 --- Francis Hackett, Lillian P. Fletcher, Arthur Bullard - Shippan Pt. beyond
98 --- Daniel Wilbur Steel, author
99 --- Rose Pastor Stokes - Portrait by Clarence Hudson White, 1909
100 --- Clarence H. White, photographer, Horace Traubel - "Caritas Island"
101 --- Stephen Marion Reynolds (Socialist), Horace Traubel
102 --- Rose Pastor Stokes - Portrait by Clarence H. White, 1909
103 --- Rose P. Stokes and JGP Stokes in Library, Stokes House - Portrait by C.H.White
104 --- Rose P. Stokes on outer island - Stokes House in background
105 --- Conrad Bercovici (Anarchist), author; JGP stokes John Corbin, drama critic; Edward Slosson, editor (feet on steps); 1907
106 --- Rose P. Stokes in "Annette Kellerman" bathing suit
107 --- Charlotte Perkins Gilman, Houghton Gilman, Rose P. Stokes playing croque
108 --- Stokes House - south elevation, winter view
109 --- Rose P. Stokes, Lillian P. Fletcher at Leroy Scott House, "Caritas Island"
110 --- Anna Pastor, mother of R. P. Stokes at Leroy Scott House
111 --- Infant John Frederick Flynn-Jones, E. Gurley Flynn (Jones), "Caritas Island"
112 --- Elizabeth Gurley Flynn (Jones), I. W. W. organizer on porch of Stokes House
113 --- John Frederick Flynn-Jones, born May 19, 1910 - August 3, 1910, "Caritas I."
114 --- J. F. Flynn-Jones in Stokes House
115 --- Lillian P. Fletcher, Rose. P. Stokes at Tom Paine Monument, New Rochelle, 1910; photograph taken by Gertrude Traubel
116 --- Picnic at Scott House - L to R, Leonard Abbott (Anarchist), Miriam Finn Scott, Horace Traubel, Leroy Scott (Socialist), author, pointing
117 --- Rockwell Kent, artist, standing; Horace Traubel near kiosk, Scott House
118 --- Rose P. Stokes, Leroy Scott, William English Walling
119 --- Horace Traubel, Leonard Abbott, Leroy Scott, Miriam Finn Scott (foreground)
120 --- Scott House - R. P. Stokes, Leonard Abbott, Horace Traubel, Miriam Finn Scott
121 --- Picnic at Scott House - Leonard Abbott, hand on the table
122 --- J. G. P. Stokes, William English Walling - Walling House beyond, left
123 --- Rockwell Kent artist
124 --- Rockwell Kent and Rose P. Stokes, "Caritas Island"
125 --- Horace Traubel and Peter Pan, dog - Stokes House beyond
126 --- Chapter heading sketch showing "Caritas Island" by Rockwell Kent in his autobiography, "It's Me, O Lord" [Removed to Subject File, Series IV, Box No. 9, Folder No. 38]
127 --- Theatricals at "Caritas Island" - William Fletcher, rear left; RPS front right
128 --- JGP Stokes, Rose P. Stokes on lawn, 1914
129 --- Houghton Gilman, Charlotte Perkins Gilman on bridge, "Caritas Island"
130 --- Charlotte Perkins Gilman, Houghton Gilman in gateway, "Caritas Island"
131 --- H. Gilman, Rose P. Stokes, Charlotte P. Gilman on steps of Stokes House
132 --- William English Walling House, "Caritas Island" - front entrance elevation
133 --- William English Walling House - west elevation
134 --- Anna Webb and Peter Pan, 88 Grove Street, New York City - Stokes city home
135 --- Anna Pastor on the lawn, "Caritas Island", summer, 1909
136 --- Merrall MacNeille, Anna Pastor (holding Allan Fletcher, grandson), John R. MacNeille in front of house occupied by Stokes (formerly Scott House), 1915-1916
137 --- Merrall MacNeille on "Caritas Island" - Wallack's Point in distance, 1916-1916
138 --- Anna Pastor Working in flower garden, "Caritas Island"
139 --- Howard Brubaker, author (later of New Yorker Magazine)
140 --- Maurice Pastor (half-brother of RPS) in U. S. Army, World War I
141 --- Maurice Pastor as a salesman
142 --- Bernard Pastor as sailor, U. S. Navy, World War I
143 --- William E. Walling children with nurse, Nantucket, August 1915; Rosamund, Anna, Georgia
144 --- View of "Caritas Island" from Schofield Island
145 --- Croquet court, "Caritas Island"
146 --- Olive Tilford Dargan, poetess, authoress (pen name: "Fielding Burke")
147 --- Lillian Pastor Fletcher, William Fletcher
148 --- Maurice Pastor (center)
149 --- Olive Tilford Dargan
150 --- Olive T. Dargan, Rose P. Stokes
151 --- Lillian P. Fletcher, son Allan - Fresh Pond, Belmont, Mass.
152 --- Lillian P. Fletcher seated in stone summer studio (over garage) "Caritas I."
153 --- Rose P. Stokes, Seymour Stedman, JGP Stokes, John Spargo - New York City
154 --- Cottage once owned by Rose Pastor Stokes (Romain), as altered, Westport, Conn.
155 --- Cottage, Westport
156 --- Pencil portrait of Anna Pastor by Rose Pastor Stokes (Owned by L. P. Fletcher)
157 --- Sheridan Square, New York City - #88 Grove Street, city home purchased, 1910
158 --- Jeanette D. Pearl, 1st wife of Louis Fraina, with whom Rose P. Stokes shared an apartment after her divorce from J. G. P. Stokes
159 --- Lillian P. Fletcher
160 --- Portrait of Rose Pastor Stokes
161 --- Portrait of Rose Pastor Stokes (1920's)